Register of the Valerian Platonovich Platonov Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Valerian Platonovich Platonov Papers
1818-1868
36005
Hoover Institution Archives
4 manuscript boxes, 3 microfilm reels (2 linear feet)
Correspondence, reports, and printed matter, relating to Russian governmental administration in Poland; political, economic, and religious conditions in Poland; and the Polish Revolution of 1863-1864. In part, microfilm from the Pilsudski Institute of America (3 reels). Collection material held at the Hoover Institution also available on microfilm (4 reels).
Platonov, Valerian Platonovich, 1809?-
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 36005
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Alternative Forms of Material Available
In part, microfilm from the Pilsudski Institute of America (3 reels). Hoover Institution holdings also available on microfilm (4 reels).
Location of Originals
In part, originals in: Pilsudski Institute of America
Biography
Russian state secretary for Polish affairs, 1864-1866.
Poland--Economic conditions.; Poland--History--Revolution, 1863-1864.; Poland--Politics and government--1796-1918.; Poland--Religion.; Poland.; Russia.; Statesmen--Russia.
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1859-1868 (Box 1-2)
  Scope and Contents note
  Correspondence arranged chronologically within the folder labelled Telegrams and alphabetically by last name of correspondent for the remaining folders.
  - Adlerberg, Alexandre, 1864 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Alekseev, Semen, 1859 (Folder 2)
  - Berg, Count
    - 1863-68 (Folder 3)
    - 1864-66 (Folder 4)
  - Bikhnevich, A., 1861 (Folder 5)
  - Bludov, Count, 1861-63 (Folder 6)
  - Borbrinskoy, 1866 (Folder 7)
  - Butskovskii, Mikhail A., 1864 (Folder 8)
  - Chevkin, K., 1864 (Folder 9)
  - Dolgorukov, Vasilii, n.d. (Folder 10)
  - Enoch, 1863 (Folder 11)
  - Golovin, n.d. (Folder 12)
  - Gorchakov, Aleksandr, 1860-65 (Folder 13)
  - Gorchakov, Mikhail D., 1859-1860 (Folder 14)
  - Hube, 1865 (Folder 15)
  - Kletande, Anton S., 1864 (Folder 16)
  - Konstantin, Grand Duke, 1862 (Folder 17)
  - Kopakowski, S., 1865 (Folder 18)
  - Korf, M., 1862 (Folder 19)
  - Kornilov, Fedor, 1861-62 (Folder 20)
  - Kryzhanovskii, Nikolai, n.d. (Folder 21)
  - Lacki, Chancellor, 1864 (Folder 22)
  - Lambert, Count de, n.d. (Folder 23)
  - Leski, 1864 (Folder 24)
  - Liders, A., 1862 (Folder 25)
  - Lubenski, Constant, 1859-1863 (Folder 26)
  - Meiendorf, Baron (Folder 27)
  - Miaskowski, M., 1863-65 (Folder 28)
  - Miliutin, D., 1862-66 (Folder 29)
  - Miliutin, Nikolai, 1863-65 (Folder 30)
  - Mukhanov, Pavel, 1860 (Folder 31)
  - Panin, Count, 1862-63 (Folder 32)
  - Potocka, Marie, n.d. (Folder 33)
  - Shuvalov, Count, n.d. (Folder 34)
  - Shuvalov, S., 1861 (Folder 35)
  - Sofiano, 1861 (Folder 36)
  - Stackelberg, E., n.d. (Folder 37)
  - Sukhozanet, General, n.d. (Folder 38)
  - Tchitchenne, B., 1866 (Folder 39)
  - Telegrams, June 1860 - December 1864 (Folder 40)
  - Trepov, F., 1864-66 (Folder 41)
  - Tripov, F.F., 1864 (Folder 42)
  - Valuiev, Count, 1861 (Folder 43)
  - Varshavskii, Prince, 1846 (Folder 44)
  - Velopol'skii, Aleksandr and Sigizmund, 1861 (Folder 45)
  - Vlangaly, A., 1884 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Westmann, 1861 (Folder 2)
  - Wotowska, C., n.d. (Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous (Folder 4)
- SUBJECT FILE, 1832-1865 (Box 2-4)
  Correspondence, notes, memoranda, reports, lists, and printed matter, arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Astrov, N.
    - Kniaz' A. A. Shcherbatov (Prince A.A. Shcherbatov) (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Stranichka iz Istorii Moskovskago Universiteta (A Little Page of History of the Moscow University), Prague, n.d. (Folder 6)
  - Biographical data
    - General (Folder 7)
    - Service record (Folder 8)
  - Glots, former president of Vlotslavka, 1862 (Folder 9)
  - Lubienski, Count (Folder 10)
  - Monitor Warszawski (Warsaw), restitution of, January 1861 (Folder 11)
  - Platonov, Sergei Fedorovich (Folder 12)
  - Poland
    - Borkowski affair, 1863 (Folder 13)
    - Civil rights of Jews, report by Count Wielopolski, 1861 (Folder 14)
    - Decree against unauthorized gatherings and public disturbances, March 1861 (Folder 15)
    - Dziennik Powszechny (Warsaw), October-November 1861 (Folder 16)
    - Elections (Folder 17)
    - Finances, 1857-1865 (Folder 18)
    - Government crimes, legal procedures (Folder 19)
    - Government employees, evaluations (Folder 20)
    - Governors of provinces, qualifications for, June 1861 (Folder 21)
    - Hospitals, 1866 (Folder 22)
    - Military courts, 1865 (Folder 23)
    - Military leaders of provinces (Folder 24)
    - Mlawa Police Court case involving unauthorized gatherings and religious singing, July 1861 (Folder 25)
    - Municipal and provincial councils, March 1861 (Folder 26)
    - Municipal courts, 1860-62 (Folder 27)
    - Peasants (Folder 28)
    - P[UNK]lock mayor's order to forbid unauthorized gatherings, July 1861 (Folder 29)
    - Railroads (Folder 30)
    - Revolution, 1863-64
      - General (Folder 31)
      - Polens letzer Aufstand (Poland's Latest Uprising), Leipzig, 1864 (Folder 32)
    - Roman Catholic Church, 1861-64 (Box 3, Folder 1-2)
    - Russian censorship of Polish literature (Folder 3)
    - Rys Ogolny Dzia[UNK]lan W[UNK]ladz Rzadowych Krolestwa Polskiego za Rok 1860 (Outline of the Activities of Government Authorities in the Kingdom of Poland for the Year 1860) (Folder 4)
    - Special State Commission of Internal Affairs, excerpts from proceedings relating to taxation of peasants in private estates, November 1861 (Folder 5)
    - State Commission of Internal Affairs, taxation of peasants in private estates, December 1861 (Folder 6)
    - State Commission of Justice, record of complaints concerning illegal behavior of Russian military authorities in the towns of Suwalki, Radom, Kielce, and others, August 1861 (Folder 7)
    - State Council
      - Decree establishing it, 1861 (Folder 8)
      - Establishment of by Nicholas I, December 24, 1832 (Folder 9)
      - Instructions on juridical and administrative litigations (Folder 10)
    - Towarzystwo Hypoteczne (Future Mortgage Bank) for Warsaw property owners, February 1859 (Folder 11)
    - Urban and rural communal courts, January 1861 (Folder 12)
    - Warsaw
      - District Counties Councils candidates (Folder 13)
      - District Criminal Court, sentence issued for disturbance case in the town of Boleslawiec, July 30, 1861 (Folder 14)
      - District of Transport, accounts of road maintenance, January 1861 (Folder 15)
      - Police Department, 1861 (Folder 16)
      - Ways of Communication Office (Folder 17)
  - Proekt Gornago Ustava (Project of Mining Regulations), n.d. (Folder 18)
  - Proposal for the establishment of an investigatory commission for political crimes in Poland, July 4, 1861 (Folder 19)
  - Russia
    - Department Vneshnei Torgovli (Department of Foreign Commerce). Proekt Ustava Russkago Zemskago Banka (The Statutes of the Russian Zemstvo Bank), St. Petersburg, 1862 (Folder 20)
    - Finances, 1864-66 (Folder 21)
    - Relations with Poland
      - Alexander II's decree regarding the establishment of provincial councils (Folder 22)
      - General (Folder 23)
      - Instructions by the Russian government regarding education in Poland, November 1861 (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - Instructions by the Russian government regarding government and political crimes in Poland (Folder 2)
      - Legal procedures in Poland (Folder 3)
  - Sale of Platonov's estate Bilgoraj, 1863-64 (Folder 4)
  - Zapiska podannaia v S. Peterburgskii Komitet o Pol'skikh Krestianakh, goda, chlenom A. Platonovym, 29 oktiabria 1858 (Folder 5)
    General note
    (Note presented to the St. Petersburg Committee, October 29, 1858, concerning Polish peasants, by member A. Platnov)
- WRITINGS, n.d. (Box 4)
  Writings arranged alphabetically by subject and title.
  - Mysl' po predmetu ustroistva i urovneniia na etom osnovanii pozemel'nykh sborov (A Thought on the Subject of Settling the Settlers and the Equalization of Tax Collections on this Basis) (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Untitled manuscripts (in Russian) concerning peasants and land use (Folder 7)
- MISCELLANY (Box 4)
  Miscellaneous notes, lists, and parts of documents.
  - Miscellaneous notes, lists, and parts of documents (Box 4, Folder 8)
- MICROFILMS, 1818-1861
  - Papers of Valerian Platonov held by the Pilsudski Institute of America, relating to Poland, 1818-1861 (Reel 1-3)
    Other Finding Aids note
    Finding aid available from the Pilsudski Institute of America: Walerian Platonow Papers, 1818-1879, Archival Fonds No. 084 http://www.pilsudski.org/portal/en/collections/archive/307-zespol-084